Guide to the Louise Hall Papers, 1934-1981
Duke University. University Archives
Louise Hall papers 1934-1981
Duke University. University Archives
Hall, Louise.
1.5 linear feet Extent: approx. 1000 Items
Louise Hall was a professor of Art and Architecture at Duke University from 1931-1975. The collection includes correspondence, memoranda, reports, printed material, clippings, color slides and papers related to the Art Department. The material ranges in date from 1934-1981.
UA.29.02.0008
Language: Material in English
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
Researchers must register and agree to copyright and privacy laws before using this collection.
Collection is open for research.
In off-site storage; 48 hours advance notice is required for use.
Provenance
The Louise Hall Papers were received by the University Archives as a transfer in 1991 and 1999.
Biographical Note
Louise Hall was born in Cambridge, MA in 1905 and was a professor of Art and Architecture at Duke University from 1931 until her retirement in 1975. She earned a B. A. from Wellesley, a B. S. from MIT, a Brevat from the University of Paris, and a Ph.D. from Harvard. A registered architect, Hall was responsible for the establishment of the curriculum in art at Duke, including the development of collections and planning for a museum. She was also Duke's representative at the Winchester [England] archaeological excavation from 1964-1971. Hall died in 1990.
Collection Overview
The collection includes correspondence, memoranda, documents related to courses and the Art Dept. as well as reports presented to the Committee on Long Range Planning. There is also material regarding space planning, the American Association of University Women and the UNC-Duke Winchester Excavation. There are color slides of the deconstruction of the Asbury Building on East Campus, printed material, some photographs of Hall, clippings and a copy of Hall's Last Will and Testament. The material ranges in date from 1934-1981.
Subject Headings
Hall, Louise; Duke University. Dept. of Aesthetics, Art, and Music; Duke University. Dept. of Art; Duke University -- Buildings; UNC-Duke Joint Committee on the Winchester Excavations; American Association of University Women; Clippings (Books, newspapers, etc.); Color slides
Related Material
News Service Biographical Files
Duke University Archives
University Archives Photographic Negative Collection
Duke University Archives
Art Association Records
Duke University Archives
Winchester Excavation Scrapbook
Duke University Archives
Contents of Collection
- Container List
  - Correspondence, 1934, 1948-1952, 1958-1959, undated (Box 1)
  - Correspondence, 1961-1965 (Box 1)
  - Correspondence, 1969-1977 (Box 1)
  - Memoranda, 1948-1949, 1956-1959, 1961-1963, 1965-1966, 1969-1973 (Box 1)
  - Art Dept. and Course-related Documents, 1946-1973 (Box 1)
  - Art Dept. Staff Meetings, 1960, 1970-1971 (Box 1)
  - Art Dept. Space Planning (Box 1)
  - Preliminary Report to the Committee on Long Range Planning, 1958 (Box 1)
  - Some Thoughts on the Arts and the Humanities in a Liberal Arts University, by Ransom R. Patrick, written for the Long Range Planning Committee, circa 1958 (Box 1)
  - Report to the Committee on Long Range Planning, 1959 (Box 1)
  - Report Appendices and Notes, circa 1958-1959 (Box 1)
  - Committees, 1958, 1961-1962, 1970-1971, 1973 (Box 1)
  - Efforts to Acquire Julian Abele Drawings, 1964, 1977 (Box 1)
  - Phi Beta Kappa, 1964-1966 (2 folders) (Box 1)
  - UNC-Duke Winchester Excavations, 1966, 1973, 1975, 1977 (Box 1)
  - Commencement, 1975 (Box 1)
  - American Association of University Women, 1957-1958 (Box 1)
  - A Center for the Fine Arts, Duke University, 1962 (Box 1)
  - Printed Material, 1934-1943 (Box 1)
  - Printed Material, 1947-1975 (Box 1)
  - Last Will and Testament, 1981 (Box 1)
  - Clippings (Box 1)
  - Miscellaneous - Notes (Box 1)
  - Miscellaneous and Photographs (Box 1)
  - Color slides of the deconstruction of Asbury Building on East Campus (5 slide boxes) (Box 1)